The volume play.
James,
if you could come up with a theme maybe
for this year's draft class, what would
it be? Yeah, I think it was exactly
that. It was
higher volume of draft capital and
ensuring that we could prioritize guys
that match and align with what I've
spoke a lot about, which are the
intangible elements, the elements that
don't necessarily always lie on the
surface, but are beneath the hood and I
think it's very clear internally that we
were able to do just that and really
excited about what lies in front. When
you look at a guy like Parker Hughes,
you nab him with your last draft pick,
what what do you see? What what jumps
out at you? Oh man, there's a ton to to
point to. Obviously, you know, the fact
that he's somebody who can run very
fast, find the football, track it down
and get ball carriers
on the ground is going to be really
helpful to our cause and you know, I got
to give our our coaching staff, our
scouting staff who in collaboration
monitor the undrafted college free agent
landscape and prioritize guys at each
position. There was a lot of heat
from not only position coaches, but also
our special teams coaches and our
scouting staff coming into the process
that made sure that he was never an
afterthought and somebody that over the
course of
this past month, Liam, myself and Camp
were able to really become intimate in
understanding what he would offer
and be able to towards the end of the
draft feel good about submitting his
name. James, the the state of your
starting lineup also your two deep
coming into the weekend, did that all
did that all allow you guys to maybe
take some more developmental prospects
today especially that you can just spend
this year
smoothing out their rough edges? Yeah,
you know, I feel good about these guys
that we've we've selected or in fact
agreed to terms with and undrafted
college free agency
competing for spots and doing their part
to level up our play and the competition
across the roster
while at the same time knowing that
there's going to be some development
required for sure and
really knowing that those guys are are
going to pour into it and you know,
we're not going to invite anybody into
this building
who isn't a strong match for it and you
know, the the idea that those that we
have
are in fact built to thrive and be the
best versions of themselves because of
the
the environment and and that alignment
with what they're actually built of and
made of I think is
is really clear in this crop. Back to
Parker.
Back to Parker. A, who found him? B, in
terms of linebacker, off-ball linebacker
philosophy, looking back at your time
with the Rams,
where things stand now through two draft
cycles in terms of the priority at the
off-ball linebacker position, where you
have found value, how would you evaluate
that? Yeah, you know, so to go to the
first portion of that question, just
like with any of the prospects, it
typically comes from
the the area scout and so A-Rob did a
great job bringing his name to the table
early in the down and had a ton of heat,
which also ultimately funneled
upward for our cross-check to then our
undrafted college free agency committee
and then ultimately through that
layered portion of interest up to the
coordinator level, myself and Liam. So
that's kind of the the transition of
ultimately his viewing and interest
level, but
as it relates to the second portion of
that question,
certainly think you can find
quality players at a ton of different
intervals and we certainly had success
towards the latter half and
latter portion of drafts and also
undrafted college free agency in Los
Angeles specifically at the linebacker
position, but nonetheless, I think that
instincts are certainly going to be
something that reigns supreme in that
space knowing that a lot happens fast
and in the specific instance of of
Parker, that stands out in a real way.
What's like one Wesley wellness? A ton.
I mean, that dude gets after it. He's
got
the makeup that aligns with everything
that we covet and the fact that he's
able to disrupt both the run and the
pass
is really a helpful piece to our cause
cuz we don't want to be too
one-dimensional defensively and in
particular, we want to stop the run and
knowing that he can do his part to
disrupt while at the same time maintain
fundamentals and techniques, it's a
really exciting piece. Five block kicks
for him, too. Oh, it's impressive and I
know like I went and watched those
specifically towards the latter half of
last week cuz I hadn't stumbled into
them. I just stumbled into something
that we called did you know and it was a
little nugget that our analytics crew
puts together on each player and as so
as I'm just reading, I was like, you
know what? I've watched all of his
defensive snaps, all of his games, but
let me go watch these kick block kicks
specifically and and then it forced me
to go back and actually watch his
special teams snaps and even on
a number of the kicks that he didn't
block, he was creating disruption and
getting really close in a lot of
instances as well. So that's certainly
more than just happenstance. It's a
unique piece that he offers. Why is he
good at it? It's hard to explain. I know
he cares,
so that's probably the first thing cuz,
you know, so many guys have talent, but
the mindset's the differentiator and I
think in that instance, it's certainly
something that I I think plays its part.
CJ Williams said he knew the Jags were
interested enough to go back and watch
every game from last season. No. What
did you find about CJ in your research
on him? That is I did not know that
nugget. That is I I felt like I held
that one close to the vest, but
nonetheless, I think he fits the bill
for a lot of the things that I've long
appreciated in wide receiver play
with both the the guys that we drafted
at the position,
they are extremely tough, extremely good
blockers, they are extremely good at
attacking the football.
So really excited about both him and
Josh entering the fray. With Josh, 528
lb squat. Oh man.
That's impressive.
>> that on film?
>> I have not seen that, but I have watched
his football play and I can understand
how he's able to do that when he's got
five guys on his back and he's still
standing, so that's that's not all that
surprising, but yeah, he is an
impressive human being. A couple
walk-ons late, college walk-ons, what
does that tell you about them? A couple
walk-ons early, you know.
>> [laughter]
>> You got to love it. I think that that is
a part to me that
says a lot. If you can start there and
end in the conversation of being a
potential draft pick, it says a lot
about
what you can overcome, being able to,
you know, when your back's against the
wall, be able to find your your path to
success and
certainly something that we think about
when we're prioritizing guys. How does
he stand out
in tight end?
I think very clearly, he's got a
superpower that he offers in a real way
and that's catching the football.
Obviously, his production over the
course of his college tenure speaks
volumes,
being one of if not the most productive
pass catcher
in college history depending on how you
look at things and
I think for how we operate, for how
Trevor
best operates, having a a big target
like that is not a bad thing especially
when it comes to red zone play. You
mentioned that the theme was volume. Did
you go in
with that plan? Like was that always in
your head that you wanted to get as many
draft picks as you could with the Rams?
Yeah, that was a big piece to even my
walk-through in the interview process. A
higher volume of draft capital was what
we were seeking and knowing that the
more at-bats you have, the better
probability
you'll have for for successful
selections while at the same time
you can have a few more hit misses than
you do hits, but nonetheless, it was
cool to lean into that as a part of this
draft and I know with 10 more that lie
in front of us in 2027 as it stands,
we're going to have a healthy three-year
run in terms of count. What was your
favorite or most memorable call from
this past three days? Oh man, I don't
know if I can say that on
on air. There there were definitely some
entertaining moments.
You always appreciate those calls
knowing that they can be
so meaningful for the guys that are
across the line and you know, while
there were a ton of emotions
for them, there were also a ton of
emotions on our end and to see our
coaching staff, our scouting staff who
have poured in a ton of time and energy
into coming to ultimately a big decision
is really just a moment where I find
myself being grateful. A moment of
gratitude to to be able to be the one to
dial,
but it's certainly a meaningful
meaningful moment and the most
entertaining ones I'll probably have to
keep off line. Now that your second
draft class is done, how much different
was this process compared to your first
one last year?
You know, I think
certainly efficient in comparison,
not being in a position where you have
to translate two different systems,
two different languages,
it just allows lines of communication to
be far more fluid. And so I think that
was a really helpful piece to to our
process and one that I have to imagine
will only continue to get more refined
and better as we move forward. James,
how do you compare him?
Gosh, I want to say
three weeks ago was when I really poured
in.
That was another one where
our area scout had a ton of interest.
Our undrafted college free agent
committee
surfaced him to the top and got us
really pouring in at a deeper level
across our over the top scouts,
coordinator level, myself and Liam.
And then if I'm not mistaken, he ended
up being a
the player that was listed in that
annual article
of go ahead and figure out who this guy
is and Brian Zanders ended up knocking
on my door and after reading it said,
"Hey, you know what? I think uh
I think he may be somebody that is going
to become more publicly aware here soon
or maybe come of interest to others if
they're able to figure it out as well.
Um but nonetheless certainly excited to
bring him into the
into the organization knowing that he's
got really a cool background, you know,
and one that
is not all that different than some of
the others that we drafted overcoming
the odds and earning their place and you
know, he was really really effective in
rushing the passer or creating
disruption this past season. James, how
do you compare what you got out of this
draft to what you wanted to get out of
it? Oh, that's a great question. Uh
so I can say
as a part of maybe the day before
uh kickoff on Thursday we ended up
putting players in slots across all 11
picks and uh can in fact say that we
were able to nail 10 of those 11 and we
only made 10 selections. So
uh that was a pretty fun outcome knowing
that we were able to map it
as cleanly as we were. I don't think
that
uh had anything to do with skill but
maybe a little more luck than that but
uh that was a pretty exciting piece.
When guys are transferring schools so
much more now than 5-10 years ago, does
that make the process for you guys the
scouting process and the investigation
process any harder or any more difficult
than it used to be? It makes it
interesting. It makes it a little bit
more of a chase while at the same time,
you know, I
when guys are only at one place for a
short period of time, you may not get a
full picture. So it's only a glimpse
typically. So you like for there to be
uh
a little bit more of a long-term
standing
uh position for you to source intel from
and not just a
someplace that they may have stopped not
just calling some version of of a stay
but I think it helps when
people are really intimate with the
player that you're you're listening to
their perspective on
um and so that bouncing around can make
it a little more challenging while at
the same time now you get a few
different more perspectives on the
matter. So
uh I don't think it hurts
uh so to speak but uh yeah, it
definitely makes the chase a little bit
more entertaining. Back to kind of
mapping out the draft, have you ever
done that before I mean in your time in
LA? season able to do That was a fun
exercise this year and um
I can say to a certain degree I would uh
but I wasn't making the decisions in Los
Angeles so that was
uh probably more on my own or off to the
side
um
whereas this one was obviously I had a
little bit more control over what
direction we actually went. Uh I know
that
Jake does that on his own, Jake Temme
and it's fun to
uh look over and cross-reference uh a
larger list of players that he would
love to choose from and uh have that be
a part of the the conversation but yeah,
that was a a unique one for this this
cycle. Did you expect to be able to hit
it like that? No.
No. So that was a fun. That was a blast.
Yeah, Tim Liam and I were just laughing
about it that
you know, that was an oddity I think. I
think that was an outlier. I wouldn't
anticipate that being the case even
moving forward. I feel like I asked this
last year but how would you
evaluate your pass rush?
That's hard to say that it's any
different than where it was
uh
you know, towards the end of last
season. I think the exciting thing from
my vantage point is we got some really
good football players across that
defensive front and our scheme is
prepped to tie not only the rush plan
but also the back end coverage together
in a way that's going to make that
really impactful.
Yeah, that could impact uh just how
quickly he's able to hit the ground
running. Uh we'll assess that a little
more closely upon arrival but uh it's
fair question because it could in fact
delay his start to
on the grass play. Everybody else good
to Everybody else is good to go.
Thank you, James.